Wake up, my friend.
醒來吧，我的朋友
I have awakened.
我甦醒了
Escaping the deathly grasp of Izanami's godly hand,
從黃泉之神伊邪那美的手中逃脫
I return to this world...
我又回到了這個世界…
Wait.
等等
You killed me.
是你殺了我
That was the last, last time, if I recall.
正確來說，那是上上次了
That's right.
對了
I was killed by Princess Izuna!
我是被伊綱公主殺的！
That means she now knows about me!
也就是說，她現在知道我的存在了
Amazing!
太棒了
She probably just sees you as a mere corpse.
她可能覺得你只是個普通的活死人吧
Your plan failed.
你的計畫失敗了
If only there was more time, it would have worked!
要是有更多時間，一定會成功的
Never mind. Your detection ability is still valuable.
沒關係，你的偵測能力還是有價值的
Let's go before this one awakens.
在他醒來之前，我們快走吧
My third wife
我的…
planted these daffodils.
第三任妻子種下了這些水仙花
The delicate blossoms somehow resembled her.
楚楚可憐的花朵有點像她
She was a great kisser, especially her tongue...
她很會接吻，尤其是她的舌頭…
No time for unnecessary chatter.
我沒空聽你講這些不重要的事
So, what are you looking for?
所以呢，妳在找什麼？
-The magatama. -Magatama?
–龍勾玉 –龍勾玉？
It's not strange for an ordinary woman to be searching for it.
平凡的女性想找這東西一點也不奇怪
It's just an ordinary item, after all.
畢竟那只是一件平凡的物品
Yes, a very ordinary possession
是啊，是一件被平凡的住持擁有 也不奇怪的
for an ordinary monk.
平凡的物品
Well, it should be in the tearoom.
對了，應該是放在茶室裡
Let me guide you there.
我帶妳過去吧
You've reached a Yokai
你打給了一個
that comes from a place beyond human knowledge.
來自人類未知空間的妖怪
Leave a message.
留言吧
Izzy! I'm coming!
伊姬！我來了！
Don't do anything foolish! No more killing!
千萬別做傻事！不可以殺人！
Have a seat.
請坐
Where's the magatama?
勾玉在哪裡？
No need to rush.
別這麼急
How about taking a break?
休息一下，喘口氣吧
This is a once-in-a-lifetime encounter.
這是一生只有一次的相會
Princess Izuna-imiki.
伊綱忌寸公主
This tea is the Tea of Submission.
這杯茶是順服茶
It has a rich aroma and is good for the skin.
香氣濃鬱，而且對皮膚很好
You're one of the Five Spears?
你是五矛會的成員嗎？
Exactly. Saigen Ninomiya at your service.
答對了，就由我二之宮齋玄 來和妳交手
First, put away that dangerous thing.
首先，把那個危險的東西收起來
Let me go.
放開我
The magatama you were looking for...
妳在尋找的龍勾玉…
Is it this?
是這個嗎？
I wanted more people
我還想讓更多的人
to see the beauty of this,
親眼目睹這塊勾玉的美
but now that a Yokai has returned to this world, I had to take it back.
但既然妖怪回到了這個世界 我必須把它拿回來
Give that to me!
把那東西交給我！
This magatama
這塊勾玉
indicates the location of what you seek.
能指引人們找到想要的東西
I tried to find the Yokai released from the World of Nothing.
我想尋找那個 從無間地獄釋放出來的妖怪
Then, that happened.
接著，有一天
This thing emitted light.
這東西發出了光芒
What were you going to look for with this magatama?
妳要用這塊勾玉來找什麼呢？
Find the Guardian of the Five Spears?
妳想找出五矛會的守護者吧？
Look.
妳看
One is right in front of you, and you didn't even have to use it.
根本不需要使用勾玉 妳面前就有一個了
I'll kill you!
我要殺了你！
To prevent being killed,
為了避免被妳殺死
let me take away your Yokai power with this.
我要用這東西奪取妳的妖力
Is it from your boyfriend?
是妳男友打來的嗎？
How pitiful of him, being pursued by a Yokai like you.
他真可憐，被妳這樣的妖怪糾纏
He came to me alone before.
之前他獨自來找我
He was looking for a way to sever the bond with you.
他想知道有什麼方法 能切斷與妳的羈絆
Didn't you know?
妳不知道嗎？
Yokai are truly not needed by anyone.
果然，妖怪是不被任何人需要的
I can sense it.
我能感覺到
Even in the darkness,
即使在黑暗中
the aura of a Yokai!
我也能察覺妖怪的氣息！
UNDER CONSTRUCTION
施工中
You can't go through!
不行，這裡不能過！
Stop!
停下來！
Izzy.
伊姬
Izzy!
伊姬！
Hachi.
小八
Izzy.
伊姬
You...
妳...
Izzy!
伊姬！
Help me!
救救我！
This woman is saying nonsense and trying to kill me!
這個女的淨說些聽不懂的話 而且還想殺我！
He's one of the Guardians of the Five Spears.
他是五矛會的守護者之一
I need his head to release my brethren.
我需要他的頭顱來釋放我的同胞
No!
不行！
-Why? -You can't kill him!
–為什麼？ –你不能殺他！
There must be another way to fulfill your mission!
一定還有別的方法能完成妳的使命！
Let's find it together!
我們一起尋找吧！
It's over.
結束了
Go. Before I change my mind.
滾吧，趁我還沒改變主意之前
Thank goodness.
我得救了
Thank goodness!
我得救了…
I'm so glad.
太好了
You're awake.
你醒來啦？
Izzy.
伊姬
What's with that outfit?
妳這身打扮是怎麼回事？
Your breakfast is ready. Hurry up.
早餐準備好了，快來吃吧
It's delicious! You're the best, Izzy.
真好吃！伊姬姊最棒了
Izzy is such a great cook.
伊姬妹妹的廚藝真的很厲害
Hurry up and eat. You'll be late for school.
怎麼了？你不吃嗎？上學會遲到的
Right, yeah.
喔，好
Can't fight on an empty stomach. Eat up.
空腹會沒有力氣戰鬥，快吃吧
Fight?
戰鬥？
Nice, Hachi.
很讚喔，小八
That's good.
你表現得很棒
Go! Nice!
上吧！很好！
Hachi, cover me.
小八，麻煩掩護我一下
Okay. Got it.
好，交給我吧
They got me!
我被幹掉了
Damn, me, too.
可惡，我也是
Hachi, the rest is up to you!
小八，剩下就交給你了
Great job!
幹得好，小八！
-That's our man! -Hachi!
–真不愧是小八！ –小八！
Hachi!
小八…
Nice, Hachi.
小八，幹得好
Yeah.
嗯
Can we make up?
我們可以和好嗎？
What are you talking about? Were we fighting?
你在說什麼？我們有吵架嗎？
What?
什麼？
Hachi, congratulations. Let's go.
小八，恭喜你，我們走吧
Hachi!
小八…
Just the two of us is better.
還是兩人獨處的感覺比較好
Yeah.
是啊
What's wrong? Want some ice cream?
怎麼了？想吃冰淇淋嗎？
The stars are beautiful.
星星真美
Hachi, let's dance.
小八，我們來跳舞吧
Sure.
好
Hachi, do you remember?
小八，你還記得嗎？
You once said it's okay to have moments where I forget my mission.
你曾經說過 偶爾暫時忘了使命也無妨
Forgetting one's mission is never allowed.
忘記自己的使命，是絕對不可原諒的
Yet, when I'm with you, I really feel like forgetting.
然而，我和你在一起時 真的幾乎就要忘了使命
Is this okay, Hachi?
這樣就好了吧，小八？
But this isn't real, is it?
但是，這一切並不是真的吧？
What are you saying?
你在說什麼？
Where is this?
這是哪裡？
Hachi, we're together now. That's what's important.
小八，我們現在在一起 這才是最重要的
I want this, too. But, sorry.
我也希望如此，但是，抱歉
I know this isn't real.
我知道這一切並不是真的
Because we can't have any of this.
因為充滿了我們無法達成的事
Don't think too much.
別想太多
Besides, there's no way you could forget your mission.
而且，妳不可能會忘記使命
Hachi, I...
小八，我…
Please! Take me back to my world.
拜託！讓我回到原本的世界
Izzy!
伊姬！
Why?
為什麼？
I had to fight.
我不得不戰鬥
You were confused.
你陷入了混亂
You killed him and showed me an illusion?
妳殺了他，讓我看見了幻象？
The moments with family, the games, the dances... All lies!
與家人相處的時光 遊戲、舞蹈…一切全是謊言
I only fulfilled my mission.
我只是完成自己的使命罷了
You killed an innocent man for a magatama?
妳為了勾玉而殺了一個無辜的人？
This man was evil.
他是邪惡的人
He was kind to us. He could have helped us.
他對我們很好 他本來說不定可以幫助我們
Don't be deceived!
你別被騙了！
He approached us with sweet words to trick us!
他打算接近我們 用花言巧語來騙我們！
That's not true.
沒這回事
He was one of the Five Spears.
他是五矛會的成員
I need his head to release my brethren.
我需要他的頭顱來釋放我的同胞
You said you'd help me.
你不是說會幫我嗎？
I just said I'd help you find the magatama.
我只說會幫妳找到勾玉
I wanted to stop you from killing.
我不希望妳繼續殺人
Stop pretending to be naive!
別再假裝天真了！
You should know my mission!
你明明很清楚我的使命！
"Pretending"?
“假裝”？
Doing the right thing isn't an act!
我是在做正確的事，不是假裝
This is absurd.
太可笑了
Am I the foolish one here?
妳覺得我可笑嗎？
Indeed, thinking I could help you was foolish!
確實，我還以為可以幫妳，太可笑了
I'm calling the police.
我要報警
No matter what, you can't escape our bond.
無論如何，你都無法擺脫我們的羈絆
I don't care about that.
我不在乎
Hachi.
小八
Why did you summon me?
你為什麼召喚我？
-It was just an accident. -No, it was fate.
–那只是一場意外 –不，是命運使然
I honestly don't understand fate,
我不懂命運
and even when I summoned you, I didn't know what would happen.
我召喚妳的時候 老實說，我根本不知道會發生什麼事
I was just lonely and foolish.
當時的我，只是個孤獨的笨蛋
At rock bottom, without hope, I tried that spell.
陷入深淵，絕望的我試了那個咒語
Then, meeting you
然後，遇見了妳
made me happy.
我很高興
But...
但是
I never wished for something like this.
我一點也不希望發生這樣的事
I'm foolish, so I still hold on to hope.
我很傻，所以直到現在還抱持希望
That things might work out between us.
相信我們之間或許能夠順利
But deep down, we know it's impossible. Right?
但我們都知道這是絕對不可能的 對吧？就連妳也很清楚
Izzy.
伊姬
Hiding...
躲躲藏藏…
Killing...
甚至殺人…
I can't do it anymore.
我沒辦法再這樣下去了
Is that what you desire?
這是你要的嗎？
You must feel the same way.
妳一定也有同樣的心情吧？
I...
我再也…
I can't stand this anymore.
受不了這一切了
Sorry.
對不起
Hachi.
小八
This is over.
一切都結束了
MUKURO POLICE STATION
六畔警察局
FIRST INVESTIGATION DIVISION
搜查一課
He's not back yet?
他還沒回來嗎？
He's probably with his girlfriend.
應該是跟女友在一起吧
Don't worry. He's a big boy.
不用擔心，忠士已經長大了
It's only his first time staying out all night. Let it pass.
只不過是第一次在外過夜 就別計較了吧
All right.
好吧
Let me know when he comes back.
他回來的時候跟我說一聲
Sir! He's gone!
警部，不好了！他不見了！
I know. My son's gone with his girlfriend.
我知道，我兒子和他女友 不知道跑去哪了
No, Kouki Shikazono is missing.
不是，鹿園弘規不見了
What are you talking about? We found his body.
妳在說什麼？我們已經找到屍體了啊
I know,
是這樣沒錯
but the body disappeared from the autopsy room, apparently?
但那具屍體 卻從解剖室中消失了，似乎是如此
This was found stuck to the medical examiner's neck.
法醫的脖子上被刺了這個
Some kind of neurotoxin, maybe?
或許是某種神經毒素？
This guy is from that underpass.
這傢伙，是從那個地下道跑出來的人
They're gone.
消失了
My dear Hikarists. Hi! Can you see me?
光粉們，大家好！看得到我嗎？
Can you guess where I am now?
你們知道我在哪裡嗎？
Turn it off.
關掉
-Why? -Why is she here?
–為什麼？ –她為什麼在這裡？
Because I needed help.
因為我們需要幫手
You were stuck by some river.
妳上次被困在某條河上
And Hachi, he's the worst.
至於小八…他最爛了
Also, I'm a Scorpio, and I like magic.
另外，我是天蠍座，我喜歡魔法
You told her about the sorcery?
你告訴她妖術的事了嗎？
Because everyone besides me seemed to know about it.
因為除了我之外，似乎所有人都知道
Just so you know, this is not a game.
我話說在前頭，這不是遊戲
Hachi's life is on the line, and so are ours.
小八的生命危在旦夕，我們也是
By the way, where are we heading?
話說，我們要去哪裡？
My hometown.
我的老家
My uncle has a collection of sorcery there,
我叔叔搜集了許多妖術
and there might be a way to counter Izzy.
或許能在那裡找到對抗伊姬的方法
Keep this in mind. We're going to send Izzy back to her world,
記住這一點 我們要把伊姬送回她原本的世界
but before that,
但在那之前
it's crucial to sever the bond between Hachi and Izzy.
必須切斷小八和伊姬之間的羈絆
If we don't unravel that connection,
如果不切斷兩人的羈絆
Hachi will be dragged into the World of Nothing.
小八也會被拖進無間地獄
What?
什麼？
You're still worried about Hachi after ending the friendship?
即使絕交了，你還是會擔心小八？
It's not like that.
才沒有
SAKON RENJO LAWYER
連城左近，律師
-Have they found Shikazono's body? -No.
–找到鹿園的屍體了嗎？ –沒有
It's peculiar how Sakon Renjo...
不過，還真奇怪，連城左近他…
Sir, Sakon Renjo
警部，是關於連城左近的事
hasn't been seen at his office for the past few days.
他果然最近幾天 都沒有出現在他的事務所裡
But take a look at this.
但是，請看這個
We found a shell company that belongs to Sakon Renjo.
我們找到一家 連城左近名下的空殼公司
A shell company?
空殼公司？
The address registered under Sakon's name is a vacant space in a mixed-use building.
這個登錄在左近名下的地址 是住商混合建築中的空房
Where is it?
在哪裡？
Around this area, I believe.
我看看…在這一帶
The heir of Ippongi Construction,
一本木建設公司的繼承人遭殺害
for which Sakon is the advisor, was killed.
左近是這間公司的顧問律師
Following Sakon's trail,
循著左近的足跡
we were attacked by a mysterious man in the underpass we found
我們發現了一條地下道 然後被神秘人士襲擊
and discovered the body of Kouki Shikazono.
之後發現鹿園弘規的屍體
Let's retrace Sakon's movements.
我們再調查一次左近去過的地方
-Yes. -Yes, sir!
–是 –是，長官！
KYOTO CITY, KYOTO PREFECTURE
京都府京都市
I see.
是嗎？
Ninomiya has...
二之宮他…
Call Sakon.
把左近叫來
I told you, Tenkai. I'm done with him.
天迴，我告訴過你，別再跟他扯上…
Ninomiya's head has fallen.
二之宮被砍頭了
What?
什麼？
Only three heads remain.
剩下三顆頭顱
They have also obtained the magatama.
對方也得到了龍勾玉
Magatama?
勾玉？
It's only a matter of time before all five heads fall.
看來五顆頭顱遲早都會被砍下
You really don't know who the fifth Guardian is?
你真的不知道第五位守護者是誰嗎？
Fifteen years ago, Goromaru transferred the power of the Guardian secretly.
15年前，五郎丸家 秘密轉移了守護者的力量
Aside from the lady herself, even the Guardians aren't aware of it.
除了那位女士之外 就連守護者自己都沒意識到這一點
If the fifth head falls,
要是第五顆頭被砍了下來
neither you nor I will get away with it so easily.
你我都不會有什麼好下場
If the fifth head falls...
要是第五顆頭被砍下的話…
That's fine. I have a plan, too.
算了，我這邊也有對策
-A plan? -Follow me.
–對策？ –跟我來
Sir.
警部？
What is this place?
這是什麼地方？
What's that smell?
這是什麼味道？
Preservation water.
是防腐水的味道
Awaken, my warriors.
醒來吧，我的戰士們
Freeze! Police!
不准動！警察！
Tadashi.
忠士
Dad.
爸爸